<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tt xml:lang="" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2006/10/ttaf1"  
 xmlns:tts="http://www.w3.org/2006/10/ttaf1#styling"
 xmlns:ttm="http://www.w3.org/2006/10/ttaf1#metadata">
  <head>
   <metadata>
    <ttm:title>President Barack Obama's Complete Inaugural Speech</ttm:title>
   </metadata>
   <styling>
      <style id="1" tts:textAlign="right"/>
      <style id="2" tts:color="transparent"/>
      <style id="3" tts:backgroundColor="transparent" tts:color="#FFCC00"/>
      <!--style id="4" style="3" tts:fontSize="+2" tts:fontFamily="Arial"  tts:textAlign="center"/-->
   </styling>
  </head>
      <body> 
        <div  xml:lang="en">
        
         <p begin='0:00:03.000' end='0:00:08.000' style="4">My fellow citizens,</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:00:08.000' end='0:00:17.000' style="4">I stand here today humbled by the task before us,</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:00:17.000' end='0:00:21.000' style="4">grateful for the trust you have bestowed,</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:00:21.000' end='0:00:26.000' style="4">mindful of the sacrifices borne by our ancestors.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:00:26.000' end='0:00:31.000' style="4">I thank President Bush for his service to our nation,</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:00:35.000' end='0:00:40.000' style="4">as well as the generosity and cooperation he has shown throughout this transition. </p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:00:43.000' end='0:00:48.000' style="4">Forty-four Americans have now taken the presidential oath. </p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:00:48.000' end='0:00:55.000' style="4">The words have been spoken during rising tides of prosperity and the still waters of peace.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:00:56.000' end='0:01:04.000' style="4">Yet, every so often the oath is taken amidst gathering clouds and raging storms. </p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:01:05.000' end='0:01:13.000' style="4">At these moments, America has carried on not simply because of the skill or vision of those in high office,</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:01:13.000' end='0:01:17.000' style="4">but because We the People</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:01:17.000' end='0:01:23.000' style="4">have remained faithful to the ideals of our forbearers, and true to our founding documents.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:01:24.000' end='0:01:30.000' style="4">So it has been. So it must be with this generation of Americans. </p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:01:32.000' end='0:01:36.000' style="4">That we are in the midst of crisis is now well understood.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:01:36.000' end='0:01:42.000' style="4">Our nation is at war, against a far-reaching network of violence and hatred.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:01:42.000' end='0:01:49.000' style="4">Our economy is badly weakened, a consequence of greed and irresponsibility on the part of some,</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:01:49.000' end='0:01:56.000' style="4">but also our collective failure to make hard choices and prepare the nation for a new age.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:01:56.000' end='0:02:00.000' style="4">Homes have been lost; jobs shed; businesses shuttered.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:02:00.000' end='0:02:03.000' style="4">Our health care is too costly; our schools fail too many; </p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:02:03.000' end='0:02:11.000' style="4">and each day brings further evidence that the ways we use energy strengthen our adversaries and threaten our planet. </p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:02:12.000' end='0:02:18.000' style="4">These are the indicators of crisis, subject to data and statistics.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:02:20.000' end='0:02:26.000' style="4">Less measurable but no less profound is a sapping of confidence across our land — </p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:02:26.000' end='0:02:34.000' style="4">a nagging fear that America's decline is inevitable, and that the next generation must lower its sights. </p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:02:36.000' end='0:02:41.000' style="4">Today I say to you that the challenges we face are real.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:02:41.000' end='0:02:43.000' style="4">They are serious and they are many.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:02:43.000' end='0:02:50.000' style="4">They will not be met easily or in a short span of time. But know this, America — they will be met. </p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:02:57.000' end='0:03:07.000' style="4">On this day, we gather because we have chosen hope over fear, unity of purpose over conflict and discord. </p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:03:07.000' end='0:03:16.000' style="4">On this day, we come to proclaim an end to the petty grievances and false promises, the recriminations and worn-out dogmas,</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:03:16.000' end='0:03:19.000' style="4">that for far too long have strangled our politics. </p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:03:21.000' end='0:03:30.000' style="4">We remain a young nation, but in the words of Scripture, the time has come to set aside childish things.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:03:30.000' end='0:03:36.000' style="4">The time has come to reaffirm our enduring spirit; to choose our better history; </p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:03:36.000' end='0:03:42.000' style="4">to carry forward that precious gift, that noble idea, passed on from generation to generation:</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:03:42.000' end='0:03:47.000' style="4">the God-given promise that all are equal, all are free,</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:03:47.000' end='0:03:51.000' style="4">and all deserve a chance to pursue their full measure of happiness.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:04:00.000' end='0:04:07.000' style="4">In reaffirming the greatness of our nation, we understand that greatness is never a given.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:04:07.000' end='0:04:14.000' style="4">It must be earned. Our journey has never been one of short-cuts or settling for less.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:04:14.000' end='0:04:17.000' style="4">It has not been the path for the faint-hearted — </p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:04:17.000' end='0:04:23.000' style="4">for those who prefer leisure over work, or seek only the pleasures of riches and fame.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:04:23.000' end='0:04:29.000' style="4">Rather, it has been the risk takers, the doers, the makers of things —</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:04:29.000' end='0:04:33.000' style="4">some celebrated but more often men and women obscure in their labor, </p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:04:33.000' end='0:04:38.000' style="4">who have carried us up the long, rugged path towards prosperity and freedom. </p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:04:40.000' end='0:04:47.000' style="4">For us, they packed up their few worldly possessions and traveled across oceans in search of a new life. </p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:04:47.000' end='0:04:56.000' style="4">For us, they toiled in sweatshops and settled the West; endured the lash of the whip and plowed the hard earth. </p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:04:56.000' end='0:05:05.000' style="4">For us, they fought and died, in places like Concord and Gettysburg; Normandy and Khe Sanh.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:05:05.000' end='0:05:14.000' style="4">Time and again these men and women struggled and sacrificed and worked till their hands were raw so that we might live a better life.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:05:14.000' end='0:05:19.000' style="4">They saw America as bigger than the sum of our individual ambitions; </p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:05:19.000' end='0:05:24.000' style="4">greater than all the differences of birth or wealth or faction. </p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:05:24.000' end='0:05:27.000' style="4">This is the journey we continue today.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:05:27.000' end='0:05:31.000' style="4">We remain the most prosperous, powerful nation on Earth.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:05:31.000' end='0:05:35.000' style="4">Our workers are no less productive than when this crisis began.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:05:35.000' end='0:05:43.000' style="4">Our minds are no less inventive, our goods and services no less needed than they were last week or last month or last year.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:05:43.000' end='0:05:47.000' style="4">Our capacity remains undiminished.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:05:47.000' end='0:05:54.000' style="4">But our time of standing pat, of protecting narrow interests and putting off unpleasant decisions —</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:05:54.000' end='0:05:57.000' style="4">that time has surely passed. </p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:05:57.000' end='0:06:06.000' style="4">Starting today, we must pick ourselves up, dust ourselves off, and begin again the work of remaking America. </p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:06:06.000' end='0:06:17.000' style="4">For everywhere we look, there is work to be done.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:06:17.000' end='0:06:22.000' style="4">The state of the economy calls for action, bold and swift, and we will act — </p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:06:22.000' end='0:06:26.000' style="4">not only to create new jobs, but to lay a new foundation for growth.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:06:26.000' end='0:06:29.000' style="4">We will build the roads and bridges,</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:06:29.000' end='0:06:34.000' style="4">the electric grids and digital lines that feed our commerce and bind us together.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:06:34.000' end='0:06:37.000' style="4">We will restore science to its rightful place, </p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:06:37.000' end='0:06:42.000' style="4">and wield technology's wonders to raise health care's quality and lower its cost. </p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:06:42.000' end='0:06:48.000' style="4">We will harness the sun and the winds and the soil to fuel our cars and run our factories.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:06:48.000' end='0:06:54.000' style="4">And we will transform our schools and colleges and universities to meet the demands of a new age.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:06:54.000' end='0:07:00.000' style="4">All this we can do. And all this we will do. </p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:07:01.000' end='0:07:06.000' style="4">Now, there are some who question the scale of our ambitions — </p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:07:06.000' end='0:07:10.000' style="4">who suggest that our system cannot tolerate too many big plans. </p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:07:10.000' end='0:07:13.000' style="4">Their memories are short.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:07:13.000' end='0:07:17.000' style="4">For they have forgotten what this country has already done; </p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:07:17.000' end='0:07:24.000' style="4">what free men and women can achieve when imagination is joined to common purpose, and necessity to courage. </p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:07:24.000' end='0:07:30.000' style="4">What the cynics fail to understand is that the ground has shifted beneath them.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:07:30.000' end='0:07:34.000' style="4">That the stale political arguments that have consumed us for so long...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:07:34.000' end='0:07:36.000' style="4">...no longer apply.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:07:36.000' end='0:07:40.000' style="4">The question we ask today is not wether our gouvernment is too big or too small...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:07:40.000' end='0:07:43.000' style="4">..but wether it works.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:07:43.000' end='0:07:46.000' style="4">Wether it helps families find jobs at a decent wage...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:07:46.000' end='0:07:49.000' style="4">...care they can afford and retirement that is dignified.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:07:49.000' end='0:07:53.000' style="4">When the answer is yes, we intend to move forward.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:07:53.000' end='0:07:56.000' style="4">When the answer is no, programms will end.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:07:56.000' end='0:08:01.000' style="4">And those of us who manage the public's dollars will be held to account...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:08:01.000' end='0:08:04.000' style="4">...to spend wisley, reform bad habits, </p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:08:04.000' end='0:08:07.000' style="4">...and do our business in the light of day...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:08:07.000' end='0:08:12.000' style="4">...because only then can we restore the vital trust between the people and their gouvernment.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:08:12.000' end='0:08:20.000' style="4">Nor is the question before us wether the market it a force for good or ill.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:08:20.000' end='0:08:24.000' style="4">Its power to generate wealth and expand freedom is unmatched.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:08:24.000' end='0:08:29.000' style="4">But this crisis has reminded us that without a watchufull eye...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:08:29.000' end='0:08:31.000' style="4">...the market can spin out of control.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:08:31.000' end='0:08:33.000' style="4">The nation cannot prosper along...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:08:33.000' end='0:08:36.000' style="4">when it favors only the prosperous.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:08:36.000' end='0:08:43.000' style="4">The success of our economy has always depended not just on the size of our gross domestic product...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:08:43.000' end='0:08:47.000' style="4">...but on the reach of our properity.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:08:47.000' end='0:08:50.000' style="4">On the ability to extend opportunty to every willing heart.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:08:50.000' end='0:08:52.000' style="4">Not out of charity...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:08:52.000' end='0:08:55.000' style="4">...but because it is the surest route to our common good.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:09:00.000' end='0:09:03.000' style="4">As for our common defence...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:09:03.000' end='0:09:10.000' style="4">...we reject as false the choice between our saftey and our ideals.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:09:10.000' end='0:09:13.000' style="4">Our founding fathers....</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:09:13.000' end='0:09:18.000' style="4">...faced with perils that we can scarcely imagine....</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:09:18.000' end='0:09:23.000' style="4">...drafted a charter to assure the rule of law and the rights of men.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:09:23.000' end='0:09:26.000' style="4">A charter expanded by the blood of generations,</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:09:26.000' end='0:09:30.000' style="4">whose ideals still light the world...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:09:30.000' end='0:09:33.000' style="4">...and we will not give them up for expediate's sake.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:09:33.000' end='0:09:40.000' style="4">And so to all the other peoples and gouvernments who are watching today...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:09:40.000' end='0:09:45.000' style="4">...from the grandest capitals to the small village, where my father was born.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:09:45.000' end='0:09:49.000' style="4">Know that America is a friend of each nation and every man, woman and child....</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:09:49.000' end='0:09:52.000' style="4">...who seeks a future of peace and dignity...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:09:52.000' end='0:09:55.000' style="4">and we are ready to lead once more!</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:10:10.000' end='0:10:15.000' style="4">Recall that earlier generations faced down fascism and communism...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:10:15.000' end='0:10:18.000' style="4">...not just with missiles and tanks...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:10:18.000' end='0:10:21.000' style="4">..but with the sturdy alliances and enduring convictions...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:10:21.000' end='0:10:24.000' style="4">They understood that our power alone cannot protect us.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:10:24.000' end='0:10:27.000' style="4">Nor does it entitle us to to as we please.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:10:27.000' end='0:10:31.000' style="4">Instead they knew that our power grows through its prudent use.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:10:31.000' end='0:10:34.000' style="4">Our security emanetes from the justness of our cause....</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:10:34.000' end='0:10:36.000' style="4">...the force of our example, </p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:10:36.000' end='0:10:40.000' style="4">the tempering qualities of humility and restraint.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:10:41.000' end='0:10:45.000' style="4">We are the keepers of this legacy.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:10:45.000' end='0:10:50.000' style="4">Guided by these priciples once more, we can meet those new threats,</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:10:50.000' end='0:10:52.000' style="4">that demand even greater effort...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:10:52.000' end='0:10:55.000' style="4">even greater cooperation and understanding between nations.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:10:55.000' end='0:10:59.000' style="4">We will begin to responibly leave Iraque to its people...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:10:59.000' end='0:11:02.000' style="4">...and forge a heard-earned peace in Afghanistan.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:11:02.000' end='0:11:06.000' style="4">With old friends and former foes we will work tirelessly...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:11:06.000' end='0:11:09.000' style="4">to lessen the nuclear threat...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:11:09.000' end='0:11:12.000' style="4">...and roll back the spectre of a warming planet.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:11:12.000' end='0:11:15.000' style="4">We will not apologize for our way of life.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:11:15.000' end='0:11:18.000' style="4">Nor will we waver in its defence.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:11:18.000' end='0:11:20.000' style="4">And for those who seek to adavance their aims by...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:11:20.000' end='0:11:23.000' style="4">...inducing terror and slaughtering innocents...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:11:23.000' end='0:11:26.000' style="4">...we say to you now that our spirit is stronger and cannot be broken...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:11:26.000' end='0:11:30.000' style="4">... you cannot outlast us and we will defeat you!</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:11:40.000' end='0:11:44.000' style="4">For we know...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:11:44.000' end='0:11:49.000' style="4">that our patchwork heritage is a stength, not a weakness.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:11:49.000' end='0:11:52.000' style="4">We are a nation of Christians an Muslims...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:11:52.000' end='0:11:55.000' style="4">... Jews and Hindus...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:11:55.000' end='0:11:57.000' style="4">...and non-believers.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:11:57.000' end='0:12:00.000' style="4">We are shaped by every language and culture...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:12:00.000' end='0:12:03.000' style="4">...drawn from every end of this earth.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:12:03.000' end='0:12:06.000' style="4">And because we have tasted the bitter swill of civil war and segregation...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:12:06.000' end='0:12:10.000' style="4">...and emerged from that dark chapters stronger and more united...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:12:10.000' end='0:12:14.000' style="4">...we cannot help but believe that the old hatreds shall someday pass...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:12:14.000' end='0:12:17.000' style="4">that the lines of tribes shall soon dissolve...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:12:17.000' end='0:12:20.000' style="4">...that as the world grows smaller our common humanity shall reveal itsself...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:12:20.000' end='0:12:25.000' style="4">...and that America must play its role in ushering in a new era of peace.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:12:25.000' end='0:12:29.000' style="4">To the Muslim world:</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:12:29.000' end='0:12:32.000' style="4">We seek a new way forward.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:12:32.000' end='0:12:35.000' style="4">Based on mutual interest and mutal respect.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:12:35.000' end='0:12:38.000' style="4">To those leaders around the globe who seek to sow conflict,</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:12:38.000' end='0:12:41.000' style="4">or blame their societies' ills on the west - </p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:12:41.000' end='0:12:44.000' style="4">know that your people will judge you on what you can build...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:12:44.000' end='0:12:47.000' style="4">...not what you destroy.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:12:47.000' end='0:12:50.000' style="4">To those....</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:12:50.000' end='0:12:55.000' style="4">...who cling to power through corruption and deceit,</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:12:55.000' end='0:12:57.000' style="4">and the silencing of dissent:</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:12:57.000' end='0:13:00.000' style="4">Know that you are on the wrong side of history.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:13:00.000' end='0:13:03.000' style="4">But that we will extend a hand</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:13:03.000' end='0:13:06.000' style="4">if you are willing to unclench your fist.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:13:06.000' end='0:13:11.000' style="4">To the people of poor nations.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:13:11.000' end='0:13:13.000' style="4">We pledge to work alongside you,</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:13:13.000' end='0:13:16.000' style="4">to make your farms flourish and let clean waters flow.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:13:16.000' end='0:13:19.000' style="4">To nurse starved bodies and feed hungry minds.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:13:19.000' end='0:13:24.000' style="4">And to those nations like ours that enjoy relative plenty:</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:13:24.000' end='0:13:29.000' style="4">We say we can no longer afford indifference to the suffering outside our borders.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:13:29.000' end='0:13:33.000' style="4">Nor can we consume the world's recourses without regard to effect.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:13:33.000' end='0:13:36.000' style="4">For the world has changed.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:13:36.000' end='0:13:39.000' style="4">And we must change with it.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:13:39.000' end='0:13:45.000' style="4">As we consider the road that unfolds before us...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:13:45.000' end='0:13:48.000' style="4">we remember with humble gratidude...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:13:48.000' end='0:13:52.000' style="4">those brave American who at this very hour....</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:13:52.000' end='0:13:55.000' style="4">patrol far-off deserts and distant mountains...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:13:55.000' end='0:13:58.000' style="4">They have something to tell us.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:13:58.000' end='0:14:03.000' style="4">Just as the fallen heroes who lie in Arlington whisper through the ages...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:14:03.000' end='0:14:08.000' style="4">We honour them not only because they are the guardians of our liberty...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:14:08.000' end='0:14:12.000' style="4">but because they embody the spirit of service.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:14:12.000' end='0:14:17.000' style="4">A willingness to find meaning in something greater than themselves.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:14:17.000' end='0:14:21.000' style="4">And yet at this moment...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:14:21.000' end='0:14:24.000' style="4">... a moment that will define a generation...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:14:24.000' end='0:14:28.000' style="4">it is precisly this spirit that must inhabit us all.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:14:28.000' end='0:14:32.000' style="4">For as much as gouvernment can do...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:14:32.000' end='0:14:35.000' style="4">..and must do...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:14:35.000' end='0:14:39.000' style="4">it is ultimatly the faith and determination of the American people upon which this nation relies.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:14:39.000' end='0:14:44.000' style="4">It is the kindness to take in a stranger when the levies break...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:14:44.000' end='0:14:46.000' style="4">the selflessness of workers...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:14:46.000' end='0:14:49.000' style="4">...who would rather cut their hours than see a friend lose their job,</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:14:49.000' end='0:14:52.000' style="4">which sees us through our darkest hours.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:14:52.000' end='0:14:55.000' style="4">It is the fire-fighter's courage, to storm a stairway filled with smoke...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:14:55.000' end='0:14:59.000' style="4">but also a parent's willingness tu nurture a child...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:14:59.000' end='0:15:02.000' style="4">...that finally decides our fate.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:15:02.000' end='0:15:07.000' style="4">Our challenges may be new...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:15:07.000' end='0:15:11.000' style="4">...the instruments with which we meet them, may be new...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:15:11.000' end='0:15:16.000' style="4">...but those values upon which our succes depends...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:15:16.000' end='0:15:19.000' style="4">...honesty and hard work...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:15:19.000' end='0:15:21.000' style="4">...courage and fair play...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:15:21.000' end='0:15:24.000' style="4">... tolerance and couriosity...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:15:24.000' end='0:15:27.000' style="4">...loyalty and patriotism...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:15:27.000' end='0:15:30.000' style="4">these things are old.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:15:30.000' end='0:15:33.000' style="4">These things are true.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:15:33.000' end='0:15:38.000' style="4">They have been the quiet force of progress throughout our history.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:15:39.000' end='0:15:44.000' style="4">What is demanded then is a return to these truths.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:15:44.000' end='0:15:48.000' style="4">What is required of us now is a new era of responsiblity.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:15:48.000' end='0:15:51.000' style="4">A recognition on the part of every American,</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:15:51.000' end='0:15:55.000' style="4">that we have duties to ourselves, our nation and the world...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:15:55.000' end='0:15:59.000' style="4">duties, that we do not grudgingly accept but rather see gladly...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:15:59.000' end='0:16:04.000' style="4">firm in the knowlegde, that there is nothing so satisfying to the spirit...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:16:04.000' end='0:16:07.000' style="4">...so defining of our character...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:16:07.000' end='0:16:10.000' style="4">...than giving our all to a difficult task.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:16:10.000' end='0:16:14.000' style="4">This is the price and the promise of citicenship.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:16:14.000' end='0:16:18.000' style="4">This is the source of our confidence.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:16:18.000' end='0:16:23.000' style="4">The knowledge that God calls on us to shape an uncertain destiny.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:16:23.000' end='0:16:26.000' style="4">This is the meaning of our liberty and our creed,</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:16:26.000' end='0:16:32.000' style="4">why men and women and children of every race and every faith can join in celebration across this magnificent mall...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:16:32.000' end='0:16:37.000' style="4">...and why a man, whose father less than 60 years ago...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:16:37.000' end='0:16:40.000' style="4">...might not have been served at a local restaurant...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:16:40.000' end='0:16:43.000' style="4">...can now stand before you...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:16:43.000' end='0:16:46.000' style="4">...to take a most sacred oath.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:16:56.000' end='0:16:59.000' style="4">So. let us part this day in rememberance...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:17:00.000' end='0:17:04.000' style="4">...of who we are and how far we have traveled.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:17:04.000' end='0:17:07.000' style="4">In the year of America's birth...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:17:07.000' end='0:17:10.000' style="4">..in the coldest of months...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:17:10.000' end='0:17:16.000' style="4">...a small band of patriots huddled by dying campfires on the shores of an icy river.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:17:16.000' end='0:17:18.000' style="4">The capital was abandonded.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:17:18.000' end='0:17:22.000' style="4">The enemy was advancing, the snow was stained with blood.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:17:22.000' end='0:17:27.000' style="4">In a moment when the outcome of our revolution was most in doubt...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:17:27.000' end='0:17:32.000' style="4">the father of our nation ordered these words be read to the people.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:17:32.000' end='0:17:36.000' style="4">"Let it be told to future world,</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:17:36.000' end='0:17:38.000' style="4">that in the depth of winter,</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:17:38.000' end='0:17:41.000' style="4">when nothing but hope and virtue could survive,</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:17:41.000' end='0:17:44.000' style="4">that the city and the country, alarmed at one common danger</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:17:44.000' end='0:17:47.000' style="4">came forth to meet it."</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:17:47.000' end='0:17:50.000' style="4">America,</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:17:50.000' end='0:17:53.000' style="4">in the face of our common dangers...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:17:53.000' end='0:17:56.000' style="4">in this winter of our hardship...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:17:56.000' end='0:17:59.000' style="4">let us remember these timeless words.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:17:59.000' end='0:18:02.000' style="4">With hope and virtue let us break once more the icy currents,</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:18:02.000' end='0:18:05.000' style="4">and endure what storms may come.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:18:05.000' end='0:18:08.000' style="4">Let it be said by our children's children</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:18:08.000' end='0:18:12.000' style="4">that when we were tested, we refused to let this journey end!</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:18:12.000' end='0:18:15.000' style="4">That we did not turn back nor did we falter!</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:18:15.000' end='0:18:19.000' style="4">And with eyes fixed on the horizon and with God's grace upon us...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:18:19.000' end='0:18:22.000' style="4">...we carried forth that great gift of freedom...</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:18:22.000' end='0:18:25.000' style="4">...and delivered it safely to future generations.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:18:25.000' end='0:18:28.000' style="4">Thank you. God bless you.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:18:28.000' end='0:18:31.000' style="4">And God bless the United States of America.</p>                              
        
        </div>
     </body>
</tt>
