<tt xml:lang="" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2006/10/ttaf1"  
 xmlns:tts="http://www.w3.org/2006/10/ttaf1#styling"
 xmlns:ttm="http://www.w3.org/2006/10/ttaf1#metadata">
  <head>
   <metadata>
    <ttm:title>Twitter in Plain English</ttm:title>
   </metadata>
   <styling>
      <style id="1" tts:textAlign="right"/>
      <style id="2" tts:color="transparent"/>
      <style id="3" tts:backgroundColor="transparent" tts:color="#FFCC00"/>
      <!--style id="4" style="3" tts:fontSize="+2" tts:fontFamily="Arial"  tts:textAlign="center"/-->
   </styling>
  </head>
      <body> 
        <div  xml:lang="en">
        
         <p begin='0:00:00.500' end='0:00:05.000' style="4">So, what are you doing? It's one of the first questions we often ask friends and family.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:00:05.000' end='0:00:10.000' style="4">Even if the answer is just mowing the lawn or cooking dinner, it's interesting to us.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:00:10.000' end='0:00:13.000' style="4">It makes us feel connected and part of each other's lives.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:00:13.000' end='0:00:18.000' style="4">Unfortunately, most of our day to day lives are hidden from people that care.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:00:18.000' end='0:00:22.000' style="4">Of course we have email and blogs and phones to keep us connected.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:00:22.000' end='0:00:25.000' style="4">But you wouldn't send an email to a friend to tell them you're having coffee.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:00:25.000' end='0:00:28.000' style="4">Your friend doesn't need to know that.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:00:28.000' end='0:00:33.000' style="4">But, what about the people that want to know about the little things that happen in your life?</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:00:33.000' end='0:00:38.000' style="4">Real life happens between blog posts and emails. And now, there's a way to share.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:00:38.000' end='0:00:41.000' style="4">This is Twitter in Plain English.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:00:41.000' end='0:00:46.000' style="4">Thanks to Twitter, it's possible to share short, bite-sized updates about your life.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:00:46.000' end='0:00:49.000' style="4">And follow the updates of people that matter to you via the Web.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:00:49.000' end='0:00:51.000' style="4">Here's how it works.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:00:51.000' end='0:00:54.000' style="4">Meet Carla. She's addicted to her mobile phone,</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:00:54.000' end='0:00:57.000' style="4">reads blogs every day, and has contacts all over the world.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:00:57.000' end='0:01:00.000' style="4">She heard about Twitter and was skeptical.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:01:00.000' end='0:01:02.000' style="4">After some of her friends couldn't stop talking about it,</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:01:02.000' end='0:01:03.000' style="4">she gave it a try.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:01:03.000' end='0:01:09.000' style="4">She signed up for free and saw that Twitter pages look a little like blogs, with very short posts.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:01:09.000' end='0:01:12.000' style="4">Each page is personal and has updates from friends.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:01:12.000' end='0:01:16.000' style="4">She got started by looking up her friends on Twitter.com.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:01:16.000' end='0:01:21.000' style="4">After finding a few, she clicked Follow to start seeing their updates on her Twitter page.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:01:21.000' end='0:01:25.000' style="4">Within hours, she began to see a different side of people she chose to follow.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:01:25.000' end='0:01:28.000' style="4">She didn't know that Steven in Seattle was a baseball fan,</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:01:28.000' end='0:01:31.000' style="4">Or that Julia in London was reading a new investment book.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:01:31.000' end='0:01:37.000' style="4">The little messages from Twitter painted a picture of her friends, family and co-workers that she'd never seen before.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:01:37.000' end='0:01:39.000' style="4">It was the real world.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:01:39.000' end='0:01:43.000' style="4">Soon, she became a fan of Twitter, and posted updates every day.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:01:43.000' end='0:01:48.000' style="4">Her friends followed her updates, and learned that she recently discovered a passion for Van Halen.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:01:48.000' end='0:01:52.000' style="4">They could see Carla's life between blog posts and emails.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:01:52.000' end='0:01:54.000' style="4">For Carla, Twitter worked because it was simple.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:01:54.000' end='0:01:58.000' style="4">The updates were always short - under 140 characters.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:01:58.000' end='0:02:00.000' style="4">Plus, she could post updates and follow her friends</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:02:00.000' end='0:02:04.000' style="4">Using the Twitter website, software on her browser,</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:02:04.000' end='0:02:07.000' style="4">a mobile phone or instant messages.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:02:07.000' end='0:02:10.000' style="4">By asking members to answer the question, What are you doing?</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:02:10.000' end='0:02:14.000' style="4">Carla found that Twitter brought her closer to people that matter to her.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:02:14.000' end='0:02:16.000' style="4">140 characters at a time.</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:02:16.000' end='0:02:20.000' style="4">Find out what your friends are doing at Twitter.com</p>                              
        
         <p begin='0:02:20.000' end='0:02:25.000' style="4">I'm Lee LeFever, and this has been Twitter in Plain English on the Common Craft Show.</p>                              
        
        </div>
     </body>
</tt>
